<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<folio name="Puzzles">
<puzzle id="0" size="4x3" ordering="days" semantic="">
<title>Blowing in the Wind</title>
<text>
<preamble>The March weather is causing mayhem all across Netherlipp and each of these three men have had their headwear unceremoniously ripped from their heads by sudden and violent gusts of wind. From the clues, can you say what type of hat each man lost on what day and where it was blown, making its retrieval almost impossible?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Zachary Zeffer watched his hat fly into the centre of the dual carriageway and under the wheels of the speeding lorries; this happened two days before Gareth Gale watched his flat cap disappear on the wind.</clue>
<clue>The bowler rose in the gusty wind like a kite and settled, eventually, at the top of a large poplar tree.</clue>
<clue>It wasn't on Wednesday that one hat ended up in the river Keigh and floated off down stream.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Man">
<item>Brendan Briese</item>
<item>Gareth Gale</item>
<item>Zachary Zeffer</item>
</category>
<category name="Hat">
<item>Baseball Cap</item>
<item>Bowler Hat</item>
<item>Flat Cap</item>
</category>
<category name="Day" keyword="date">
<item>Monday</item>
<item>Wednesday</item>
<item>Friday</item>
</category>
<category name="Blown">
<item>Dual Carriageway</item>
<item>River</item>
<item>Tree</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Brenadan Briese, bowler hat, Monday, treetops},{Gareth Gale, flat cap, Friday, river},{Zachary Zeffer, baseball cap, Wednesday, dual carriageway}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="1" size="4x3" ordering="" semantic="">
<title>Rainy Day Women</title>
<text>
<preamble>The unpredictable March weather continues to be predictably bad and each of these three women got caught in the sort of downpour that has Biblical patriarchs reaching for the plans marked 'Arl'. Not having a brolly, they each ducked through the nearest door to avoid the cloudburst only to find themselves in a shop. From the clues, can you say where each woman was going, the name of the shop whose door she ran through and the item she felt obliged to buy while sheltering?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The lady who dashed through the door of Lee's Key Cutting and Shoe Repairing emporium felt obliged to have a spare back door key cut.</clue>
<clue>Denise De Luge was on her way to the dentist when she needed to seek refuge through the nearest door; the port in a storm for Stephanie Storm was Port's shop.</clue>
<clue>The person on her way to work wasn't the one who found herself in a menswear shop and came out with a pair of long socks.</clue>
<clue>The lady on her way to Netherlipp Market found herself sheltering in a baker's and felt obliged to buy a scone, which didn't do much for the diet she was supposed to be following.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Woman">
<item>Denise De Luge</item>
<item>Rachel Rayner</item>
<item>Stephanie Storm</item>
</category>
<category name="Going to">
<item>Dentist</item>
<item>Market</item>
<item>Work</item>
</category>
<category name="Shop">
<item>Haven's</item>
<item>Lee's</item>
<item>Port's</item>
</category>
<category name="Item bought">
<item>Key</item>
<item>Scone</item>
<item>Socks</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Denise De Luge, dentist, Haven's, socks},{Rachel Rayner, work, Lee's, key},{Stephanie Storm, market, Port's, scone}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="2" size="4x4" ordering="currency" semantic="gender">
<title>Raising...</title>
<text>
<preamble>This week at RKO (Radio Keighshire Oldies) is Appeal Week raising much needed funds for local good causes. Four DJs have hosted the mid-morning show so far and each has received pledges to play certain songs and auctioned a particular item or opportunity. From the clues, can you say which singer or band's song raised the most during each DJ's show, the item they auctioned and the amount of money the show made as a whole?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Delia Johnson's show raised more money than the one that auctioned glider lessons at Lower Marsh Airfield but less money than the one whose top song was "Guitar Man" by Bread.</clue>
<clue>The show in which Bucks Fizz's "Making Your Mind Up" was the top earner raised more cash than the show which auctioned the opportunity to be RKO's Saturday morning guest DJ next week but less than Debbie Jenkin's show.</clue>
<clue>Daniel Jeffries' show raised more money than the one that featured "Cracklin' Rosie" by Neil Diamond but less than the one that auctioned the backstage pass for the Netherlipp Apollo's 60s night.</clue>
<clue>The show that raked in the cash with Johnny Cash's "Ring of Fire" made £250 more than Duncan Joseph's.</clue>
<clue>A male DJ auctioned a hospitality package for Netherliipp United's match with Athletico Stonekeigh.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="DJ">
<item>Daniel Jeffries</item>
<item>Debbie Jenkins</item>
<item>Delia Johnson</item>
<item>Duncan Joseph</item>
</category>
<category name="Singer/Band">
<item>Bread</item>
<item>Bucks Fizz</item>
<item>Neil Diamond</item>
<item>Johnny Cash</item>
</category>
<category name="Auction">
<item>Backstage Pass</item>
<item>Football Hospitality</item>
<item>Gliding Lessons</item>
<item>Guest DJ</item>
</category>
<category name="Money raised" keyword="currency">
<item>£1,500</item>
<item>£1,750</item>
<item>£2,000</item>
<item>£2,250</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Daniel Jeffries, Bucks Fizz, football hospitality, £2,000},{Debbie Jenkins, Bread, backstage pass, £2,250},{Delia Johnson, Johnny Cash, guest DJ, £1,750},{Duncan Joseph, Neil Diamond, glider lessons, £1,500}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="3" size="4x4" ordering="" semantic="">
<title>...the Bar</title>
<text>
<preamble>The rules at the Central Criminal Court in Netherlipp are often thought to compel the wearing of wigs by barristers but the events this morning in courts 1 to 4 have shown that not to be the case. Rule 25 subsection F paragraph 5a states 'The attendance of a barrister at the chancery will be suffered on condition of the presence of a headdress' and so when the four barristers arrived at the courts only to realise they had forgotten to bring their wigs, they improvised. From the clues, can you say in which court, presided over by which judge, each barrister appeared and the item they hastily conscripted as a headdress?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Barrister Damien Dowte, wearing the head of a mop on his head, strode as unselfconsciously as he could, into court at 9am; the judge presiding was not Judge De Cree who wasn't presiding in the court with barrister Garfield Grille, who wasn't at work in court 4.</clue>
<clue>'Excuse me,' said Judge Deam, hardly able to believe his eyes, 'is that a book on your head?' 'Yes, sir' replied the barrister, '"The Old Curiousity Shop", first edition.'</clue>
<clue>Judge Rufus Roole, overseeing proceedings in court 3 of the central Court, was not confronted with a barrister wearing an item fashioned from a brown paper bag and some vaguely remembered origami.</clue>
<clue>Reginald Rangle, putting the case for the defene in court 2, was not the barrister who turned up for work with a knotted handkerchief on his head.</clue>
<clue>Judge Gaige was presiding in the court numbered one higher than the one where barrister Quentin Quarrell was modelling an unconventional style of headwear.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Court" keyword="numeric">
<item>Court 1</item>
<item>Court 2</item>
<item>Court 3</item>
<item>Court 4</item>
</category>
<category name="Judge">
<item>Judge Deam</item>
<item>Judge De Cree</item>
<item>Judge Gaige</item>
<item>Judge Roole</item>
</category>
<category name="Barrister">
<item>Damien Dowte</item>
<item>Garfield Grille</item>
<item>Quentin Quarrell</item>
<item>Reginald Rangle</item>
</category>
<category name="Headdress">
<item>Book</item>
<item>Handkerchief</item>
<item>Mop</item>
<item>Paper bag</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Court 1, Judge Deam, Garfield Frille, book},{Court 2, Judge De Cree, Reginald Rangle, paper bag},{Court 3, Judge Roole, Quentin Quarrel, handkerchief},{Court 4, Judge Gaige, Damien Dowte, mop}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="4" size="4x4" ordering="days" semantic = "">
<title>Tucking In</title>
<text>
<preamble>Each of our new friends, the four lads of dormitory B4 at St Keigh's Boarding School, have received a parcel containing something for their tuck box. The school matron, who is in charge of such things, has strict rules about tuck, keeping its consumption to a minimum as a treat. So the lads of B4 sneaked their parcels into the dormitory and enjoyed a midnight feast of the whole lot over four nights. From the clues, can you work out which relative sent which boy what tasty morsel and on which night they wolfed the lot?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The large fruit cake sent to St Keigh's by one lad's Aunt Amelia wasn't the last tuck to be polished off.</clue>
<clue>Hamish Hazel gratefully received a food parcel from his  grandmother; Martin masters was sent a package for his tuck box by his aunt.</clue>
<clue>Chris Cockcroft's package contained a very large tin of biscuits.</clue>
<clue>Aunt Alison's offering to her nephew was gobbled the day before the offering from one lad's mum and the day after the jumbo tin of toffee was noshed.</clue>
<clue>The monster bag of wine gums was not sent to Ben Barton.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Name">
<item>Barton</item>
<item>Cockcroft</item>
<item>Hazel</item>
<item>Masters</item>
</category>
<category name="Tuck">
<item>Biscuits</item>
<item>Fruit cake</item>
<item>Toffee</item>
<item>Wine gums</item>
</category>
<category name="Sent by">
<item>Aunt Alison</item>
<item>Aunt Amelia</item>
<item>Grandmother</item>
<item>Mother</item>
</category>
<category name="Night eaten" keyword="date">
<item>Monday</item>
<item>Tuesday</item>
<item>Wednesday</item>
<item>Thursday</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Ben Barton, fruit cake, Aunt Amelia, Monday},{Chris Cockcroft, birscuits, mother, Thursday},{Hamish Hazel, toffee, grandmother, Tuesday},{Martin Masters, wine gums, Autn Alison, Wednesday}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="5" size="4x4" ordering="" semantic = "gender">
<title>Nip and Tuck</title>
<text>
<preamble>The Keighshire Universal Therapy and Surgical Hospital for Upgrades and Tweaks, known locally as the Kut'n'Shut, is a cosmetic surgery facility for those people not happy with the way nature or time has arranged their features. This week four local celebrities are resident, having small modifications made to their visages. From the clues, can you work out the field in which each celeb has made his or her name, the part of their face they are having tweaked and the surgeon carrying out the operation?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Pamela Prowed is unhappy with her nose and is at the Kut'n'Shut to have it repointed; she isn't an author.</clue>
<clue>Selwyn Smugge is the star of the NetherlippTV programme 'Smugge's Way'; the lead singer of the pop group Vanity Parade is having the wrinkles removed from their forehead.</clue>
<clue>Samantha Selffe's surgeon is a woman, the movie star's scalpel wielder is male.</clue>
<clue>Humphrey Hacker is the surgeon who is pinning one celebrity's ears back again - they seem to have a mind of their own.</clue>
<clue>Neither Vernon Vayne, nor the celebrity having their chin reduced (or enlarged or sharpened or something) is going under the knife wielded by surgeon Lucille Loppett.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Celebrity">
<item>Pamela Prowed</item>
<item>Samantha Selffe</item>
<item>selwyn Smugge</item>
<item>Vernon Vayne</item>
</category>
<category name="Famed for">
<item>Author</item>
<item>Movie star</item>
<item>Pop singer</item>
<item>TV star</item>
</category>
<category name="Part">
<item>Chin</item>
<item>Ears</item>
<item>Forehead</item>
<item>Nose</item>
</category>
<category name="Surgeon">
<item>Cherry Chopper</item>
<item>Conrad Carver</item>
<item>Humphrey Hacker</item>
<item>Lucille Loppett</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Pamela Prowed, movie star, nose, Conrad Carver},{Samantha Selffe, pop star, forhead, Lucille Loppett},{Selwyn Smugge, TV star, chin Cherry Chopper},{Vernon Vayne, author, ears, Humphrey Hacker}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="6" size="4x5" ordering="months, item length" semantic = "transport">
<title>Monster and Wife</title>
<text>
<preamble>Karl Borisov killed his wife five times last year - all, of course, on film. Karl is reckoned one of the best monsters in the movie business, and it's in his contract that, if you hire him, you hire her as well, to play a small role as one of the monster's victims - she's not a great actress. From the clues below, can you work out which film was released in each of the listed months, what monster he played in it, and his wife Gloria's smaller role?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>In 'Congo of Terror', Karl appears as an alien cyborg (an organic robot, if you can get your head round that idea), and Gloria plays a passenger in some form of transport; 'Intruder' is not the film that features Karl as a particularly violent, particularly hairy werewolf.</clue>
<clue>'Shadow of Fear' was realeased in March.</clue>
<clue>In the January release, which is not called 'It Walks by Night', Karl plays a mutant ape but Gloria doesn't play the 'woman in pub' who dies nastily at the hands of another scary monster.</clue>
<clue>The film in which Karl played a bunyip (a man-eating Australian monster) came out four months after the one in which Gloria took the role of 'housewife on bus', one of a group of three slain by her husband's character.</clue>
<clue>The nun on the train in a (very minor) character in the July release, which has a one-word title.</clue>
<clue>One film features Karl as a vampire and Gloria as a woman in a taxi who is one of his early victims.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Month" keyword="months">
<item>January</item>
<item>March</item>
<item>May</item>
<item>July</item>
<item>September</item>
</category>
<category name="Title" keyword="length">
<item>Bloodbeast</item>
<item>Congo of terror</item>
<item>Intruder</item>
<item>It Walks By Night</item>
<item>Shadow of Fear</item>
</category>
<category name="Karl's Role">
<item>Alien cyborg</item>
<item>Bunyip</item>
<item>Mutant ape</item>
<item>Vampire</item>
<item>Werewolf</item>
</category>
<category name="Gloria's Role">
<item>Housewife on bus</item>
<item>Nun on train</item>
<item>Policewoman</item>
<item>Woman in pub</item>
<item>Woman in taxi</item>
</category>
<solution>{{January, Intruder, mutant ape, policewoman},{March, Shadow of Fear, vampire, woman in taxi},{May, Cargo of Terror, alien cyborg, housewife on bus},{July, Bloodbeast, werewolf, nun on train},{September, It Walks By Night, bunyip, woman in pub}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="7" size="4x5" ordering="time, numeric" semantic = "">
<title>Cometh the Hour</title>
<text>
<preamble>...whereth the slave? Each of our five acquaintances, the slovenly slaves of Ancient Rome, had been commanded to meet their long-suffering master at a specific spot in the city at a particular hour of the day. (The Romans measure time by the number of hours, from 1 to 12, after sunrise.) But, as you might expect, each miserable minion failed to show up at the appointed time. From the clues, can you work out at what hour each slave was supposed to attend which place and the excuse they proffered?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The slave who was supposed to turn up at prima luce (first light) blamed his dog, who should have woken him.</clue>
<clue>Cluelus' master was left waiting at the Senate House later in the day than the master waiting at the amphitheatre.</clue>
<clue>The slave who was late at the banker's stall said he hadn't noticed the candle clock had blown out; this meeting was later in the day than the one missed by Euselus.</clue>
<clue>The meeting missed by Branelus, who claimed that the pointer on Augusts' Obelisk Clock was badly positioned, was earlier in the day than that of the slave who blamed a leak in the water clock.</clue>
<clue>One slave was commanded to be at the Flaminian Gate at the 11th hour; Hopelus should have turned up at the 3rd hour, but didn't.</clue>
<clue>The slave who blamed a cloud obscuring the sundial, who was to meet his master later in the day than the one who should have been at the baths, wasn't Gormlus; the baths was not the site of the first meeting of the day.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Slave">
<item>Branelus</item>
<item>Clueles</item>
<item>Euselus</item>
<item>Gormlus</item>
<item>Hopelus</item>
</category>
<category name="Location">
<item>Amphitheatre</item>
<item>Baker's stall</item>
<item>Baths</item>
<item>Flaminian Gate</item>
<item>Senate House</item>
</category>
<category name="Hour" keyword="ordinal">
<item>Prima luce</item>
<item>3rd hour</item>
<item>6th hour</item>
<item>8th hour</item>
<item>11th hour</item>
</category>
<category name="Excuse">
<item>Candle blown out</item>
<item>Clouds</item>
<item>Dog overslept</item>
<item>Obelisk wrong</item>
<item>Water leak</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Branelus, baths, 6th hour, Obelisk wrong},{Cluelus, Senate House, 8th hour, clouds},{Euselus, amphitheatre, prima luce, dogs overslept},{Gormlus, Flaminian Gate, 11th hour, water leak},{Hopelus, banker's stall, 3rd hour, candle blown out}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="8" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "gender">
<title>First of April Mail</title>
<text>
<preamble>Five employees at PennyCorps' administrative complex in Storbury received letters on April 1st containing good or bad news, and each of the five, aware of the date, laughed and threw it in the bin - and four of them were right! From the clues given, can you work out each person's name and job, what their letter was about and who sent it?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The Security officer discovered - on the evening of April 1st - that her letter had been sent by her younger brother.</clue>
<clue>Helen Jakin received a red printed 'final warning' regarding an unpaid gas bill - but lives in an all-electric home.</clue>
<clue>Sam Tilney, whose letter came from his sister but did not bear her signature, doesn't work in Human Resources and was not the recipient of the extremely realistic-looking eviction order.</clue>
<clue>The woman from Advertising has been with PennyCorp since 1995.</clue>
<clue>Mandy Nolan from Accounts didn't receive the notification of a £10,000 lottery win, which wasn't sent to the employee from Catering or by anybody's best friend.</clue>
<clue>The woman whose letter actually came from a workmate wasn't Diane Eden and doesn't work in Accounts.</clue>
<clue>Anybody could have acquired a sheet of official PennyCorp notepaper and fabricated a letter telling a worker that they were getting a raise - but, in fact, that document, which didn't go to Barry Cobb, did come from PennyCorp and was absolutely genuine.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Name">
<item>Barry Cobb</item>
<item>Diane Eden</item>
<item>Helen Jakin</item>
<item>Mandy Nolan</item>
<item>Sam Tilney</item>
</category>
<category name="Department">
<item>Accounts</item>
<item>Advertising</item>
<item>Catering</item>
<item>Human Resources</item>
<item>Security</item>
</category>
<category name="Received">
<item>Eviction order</item>
<item>Final warning</item>
<item>Lottery win</item>
<item>Parking ticket</item>
<item>Raise</item>
</category>
<category name="Sender">
<item>Best friend</item>
<item>Brother</item>
<item>PennyCorp</item>
<item>Sister</item>
<item>Workmate</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Barry Codd, Human Resources, eviction order, best friend},{Diane Eden, Security, lottery win, brother},{Helen Jakin, Advertising, final warning, workmate},{Mandy Nolan, Accounts, raise, PennyCorp},{Sam Tilney, Catering, parking ticket, sister}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="9" size="4x5" ordering="currency" semantic = "">
<title>Fortunes of War</title>
<text>
<preamble>The title of this problem is also the title of a new book by historian Job Dunn which looks at five Americans who made their fortunes in various ways during the Second World War. From the clues below, can you work out each man's name, where in the USA he came from, how he obtained (not, in most cases, earned) his fortune, and how much he made?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The man from Mobile, Alabama, who made his fortune from German bullion he and a group of other soldiers stole during the liberation of Italy, was not Anson Burgess and did not end up with $8 million.</clue>
<clue>Jack Keller's fortune, made in the black market, was six million dollars more than that of the man from Fresno, California.</clue>
<clue>The man who made his fortune more or less legitimately from the military contracts filled by his family's clothing factory ended up with more money than Lou Mazzini.</clue>
<clue>Curtis Donleavy from New York City was not the man who made $11 million by dealing in works of art stolen by the Nazis and then stolen from them by his organisation.</clue>
<clue>The man from St Louis, Missouri, finished up with a modest fortune of just $5 million.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Name">
<item>Anson Burgess</item>
<item>Curtis Donleavy</item>
<item>Jack Keller</item>
<item>Lou Mazzini</item>
<item>Ray Starke</item>
</category>
<category name="Home">
<item>Dayton</item>
<item>Fresno</item>
<item>Mobile</item>
<item>New York City</item>
<item>St Louis</item>
</category>
<category name="Acquired">
<item>Aircraft Manufacture</item>
<item>Black market</item>
<item>Military contracts</item>
<item>Sold stolen art</item>
<item>Stole German bullion</item>
</category>
<category name="Amount" keyword="currency">
<item>$5 million</item>
<item>$8 million</item>
<item>$11 million</item>
<item>$14 million</item>
<item>$17 million</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Anson Burgess, Fresno, sold stolen art, $11 million},{Curtis Donleavy, New York City, military contracts, $8 million},{Jack Keller, Dayton, black market, $17 million},{Lou Mazzini, St Louis, aircraft manufacture, $5 million},{Ray Starke, Mobile, stolen German Bullion, $14 million}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="10" size="4x5" ordering="weekdays" semantic = "">
<title>Night's Out</title>
<text>
<preamble>Amanda Night, long term resident of the village of Much Lerning, keeps herself occupied during the week by attending a different minority interest club each night. The clubs are held in different locations around the village and are run by different organisers. From the clues, can you say where Amanda goes each night, what she does and with whom?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The fern arranging lessons are organised by K Bullcarr but these sessions are not held in Much Learning Village Hall.</clue>
<clue>The classes organised by A Powse on Friday evenings are not the card playing lessons.</clue>
<clue>The Community Centre is used by the club organised by O Penning, which takes place two days later in the week than the lessons which are held in the Much Lerning Primary School.</clue>
<clue>The Goldfish Society, where Amanda goes with her fish Brian, meets in a room at the Much Lerning Library the day before the String art group meets; M T Wallitt does not organise Wednesday's event.</clue>
<clue>The Village Hall is used on Monday.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Club">
<item>Card playing</item>
<item>Fern arranging</item>
<item>Goldfish Society</item>
<item>String art</item>
<item>wine pouring</item>
</category>
<category name="Location">
<item>Community centre</item>
<item>Friend's house</item>
<item>Library</item>
<item>Local school</item>
<item>Village hall</item>
</category>
<category name="Day" keyword="days">
<item>Monday</item>
<item>Tuesday</item>
<item>Wednesday</item>
<item>Thursday</item>
<item>Friday</item>
</category>
<category name="Organiser">
<item>A Powse</item>
<item>D Marcks</item>
<item>K Bullcarr</item>
<item>M T Wallitt</item>
<item>O Penning</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Card playing, Village hall, Monday, M T Wallitt},{Fern arranging, Local school, Tuesday, K Bullcarr},{Goldfish Society, Library, Wednesday, D marcks},{String art, Community centre, Thursday, O Penning},{Wine pouring, Friend's house, Friday, A Powse}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="11" size="4x5" ordering="initial letter" semantic = "gender">
<title>Green Stuff</title>
<text>
<preamble>Five pupils from Miss Lyme's class at Brunswick Green Primary School participated in the planting of trees on the village's new community woodland last week. From the clues below, can you work out each child's full name, how they earned the privilege of planting a tree, and what sort of tree they planted?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Hayden - who has a Welsh first name because he has a Welsh mother - planted a beech tree.</clue>
<clue>Lynn, who was invited to plant a tree because of the success of her butterfly-raising project, did not plant a tree with a name starting with an 'h'.</clue>
<clue>Young Lincoln, who did not write the poem about animals, planted a hornbeam sapling; he or she was not Claire.</clue>
<clue>Young Parris, who planted and maintained a productive vegetable garden, didn't plant the hawthorn tree,</clue>
<clue>Samantha Kelly was not the pupil who planted a pedunculate oak after winning the school's essay contest with a piece about conservation.</clue>
<clue>Lynn's surname isn't Moss.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="First name">
<item>Claire</item>
<item>Hayden</item>
<item>Lynn</item>
<item>Philip</item>
<item>Samantha</item>
</category>
<category name="Surname">
<item>Bottle</item>
<item>Kelly</item>
<item>Lincoln</item>
<item>Moss</item>
<item>Parris</item>
</category>
<category name="How earned">
<item>Growing vegetables</item>
<item>Poem about animals</item>
<item>Raising butterflies</item>
<item>Won essay contest</item>
<item>Won painting contest</item>
</category>
<category name="Tree planted" keyword="alphabet">
<item>Beech</item>
<item>Cherry</item>
<item>Hawthorn</item>
<item>Hornbeam</item>
<item>Oak</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Claire, Moss, won essay contest, oak},{Hayden, Parris, growing vegetables, beech},{Lynn, Bottle, raising butterflies, cherry},{Philip, Lincoln, won painting contest, hornbeam},{Samantha, Kelly, poem about animals, hawthorn}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="12" size="4x5" ordering="time" semantic = "">
<title>Village Constable</title>
<text>
<preamble>Back in the 1950s, PC Alan Richards was the village policeman in Peacethorpe, on the moors north of Northchester, and enjoyed a fairly quiet life. For instance, on Monday, May 2nd, 1955, he received five phone calls, dealt with each in less than an hour and spent the rest of the time digging his garden. From the clues, can you work out who rang him at each of the listed times, where from and what about?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The 10.00am phone call, which wasn't from Mrs Holt, concerned a missing bicycle, which Alan recovered from the garden of the local drunk - who 'borrowed' it at least once a month - and returned before 10.30am.</clue>
<clue>Mr Garth from Hazel Cottage rang Alan two hours after one of the other villagers phoned to invite the constable to dinner on Tuesday.</clue>
<clue>The call about the window broken by a group of young footballers (who Alan admonished and sent on their way after collecting enough from them to pay for the damage) came two hours after Miss Cass' and two hours before the one from Manor Farm.</clue>
<clue>At 2.00pm, Alan got a call from a teacher at St Anne's School, at the other end of the village from his police house.</clue>
<clue>Mr Jones, who rang to say that he had finished the car maintenance manual Alan had lent him, didn't phone from Kendall House or the school.</clue>
<clue>It was the call from Wolfstone Farm that alerted Alan to a horse running loose on the Northchester road, which he was able to secure and return to its owner's field within forty minutes.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Call time" keyword="time">
<item>10.00am</item>
<item>12.00 noon</item>
<item>2.00pm</item>
<item>4.00pm</item>
<item>6.00pm</item>
</category>
<category name="Caller">
<item>Miss Cass</item>
<item>Mrs Deane</item>
<item>Mr Garth</item>
<item>Mrs Holt</item>
<item>Mr Jones</item>
</category>
<category name="From">
<item>Hazel Cottage</item>
<item>Kendall House</item>
<item>Manor Farm</item>
<item>St Anne's School</item>
<item>Wolfstone Farm</item>
</category>
<category name="Reason">
<item>Broken window</item>
<item>Finished borrowed book</item>
<item>Invitation to dinner</item>
<item>Loose horse</item>
<item>Missing bicycle</item>
</category>
<solution>{{10.00am, Mrs Deane, Kendall House, missing bicycle},{12.00 noon, Mrs Holt, Wolfstone Farm, loose horse},{2.00pm, Miss Cass, St Anne's School, invitation to dinner},{4.00pm, Mr Garth, Hazel Cottage, broken window},{6.00pm, Mr Jones, Manor Farm, finished borrowed book}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="13" size="4x5" ordering="ordinal" semantic = "lots">
<title>Fan's Phone-in</title>
<text>
<preamble>with the excitement of the day's football matches over, SportRadio's top presented Hank Erman hosts a phone-in programme for fans returning home to discuss the afternoon's events. Usually the programme is taken up with disgruntled callers demanding the manager's head on a plate or the replacement of the team's entire back four, but the five callers on tonight's show have other grumbles. From these snippets of the programme (not given in their order of appearance), can you give the order in which the caller's spoke, the team they support, and the complaint they feel the rest of the country needs to hear?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>"OK", began Hank, "who's first?" "It's me," said a voice, "I've been to Vilaston and I'm purple with rage."</clue>
<clue>"Well, that was a passionate call from a Chersterman City fan," said Hank, "let's move on to Landsunder fan Bert Bellyache." "It's Belli ah chee, actually Hank."</clue>
<clue>"I arrived at the Swanpool ground," said an incensed caller, "and the car park was full. It's unacceptable!"</clue>
<clue>"Who's our third caller?" Hank asked his producer. "It's Morris Nutter, although it might be Mutter," came the reply.</clue>
<clue>"That was Grahan Gripe," said Hank, "Do you agree with him that all players need a haircut? Next up it's Barry Beef and don't worry there's still time to get your call in. Now Barry, you're an Oldcastle fan, right?" "Not a chance, no way, never" replied Barry.</clue>
<clue>"Well," said Hank, "we've arrived at our last call, let's hope it's a more important subject." "It certainly is," replied the caller, "and it's got me really riled. There's definitely less steak in the steak and kidney pies."</clue>
<clue>"That's another show done," said Hank summing up, "We heard Greg Growse, who got a bit annoyed when I suggested he supported Chesterman and we heard a complaint about the new shirt colour some time before the chap who was annoyed that the programme price had gone up 10p; was he an Oldcastle fan? No, that's right he was from... Oh I give up, goodnight."</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Order" keyword="ordinal">
<item>First</item>
<item>Second</item>
<item>Third</item>
<item>Fourth</item>
<item>Fifth</item>
</category>
<category name="Caller">
<item>Barry Beef</item>
<item>Bert Bellyache</item>
<item>Graham Gripe</item>
<item>Greg Growse</item>
<item>Morris Mutter</item>
</category>
<category name="Team">
<item>Chesterman City</item>
<item>Landsunder</item>
<item>Oldcastle Utd</item>
<item>Swanpool</item>
<item>Vilaston</item>
</category>
<category name="Complaint">
<item>Car park</item>
<item>Haircut</item>
<item>Pies</item>
<item>Programme price</item>
<item>Shirt colour</item>
</category>
<solution>{{First, Graham Gripe, Vilaston, haircut},{Second, Barry Beef, Swanpool, car park},{Third, Morris Mutter, Chesterman City, shirt colour},{Fourth, Bert Bellyache, Landsunder, programme price},{Fifth, Greg Growse, Oldcastle Utd, pies}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="14" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "">
<title>Corodale Enders</title>
<text>
<preamble>The Netherlipp TV soap "Corodale Enders" has been on our screen for so long that some of its stars find it difficult to separate reality from fiction. From the clues, can you help them to find their true identity, by giving the first name and surname of the person playing each character and their occupation in the series?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Oliver Newton does not play the part of either a corner shop owner or a graphic designer working from a studio in their attic.</clue>
<clue>The star named Lemming plays Pat Thistle in the soap; the one called Dover does not play Wanda Abbott or the designer.</clue>
<clue>Gareth's surname isn't Buckitt and Julian isn't the star who portrays the particularly dodgy Harry Lymes in the soap.</clue>
<clue>Marlene plays the part of Sam Gomez but she is not a taxi driver or a bar assistant.</clue>
<clue>The owner of the corner shop in "Corodale Enders" is Wanda Abbott, but this character is not played by Julian; the star named Parkes plays the taxi driver, whose car is usually seen parked outside the cafe, but the name of this character is not RU O'Kaye.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="First name">
<item>Eleanor</item>
<item>Gareth</item>
<item>Julian</item>
<item>Marlene</item>
<item>Oliver</item>
</category>
<category name="Surname">
<item>Buckitt</item>
<item>Dover</item>
<item>Lemming</item>
<item>Newton</item>
<item>Parkes</item>
</category>
<category name="Character">
<item>Harry Lymes</item>
<item>Pat Thistle</item>
<item>RU O'Kaye</item>
<item>Sam Gomez</item>
<item>Wanda Abbott</item>
</category>
<category name="Occupation">
<item>Bar assistant</item>
<item>Designer</item>
<item>Police officer</item>
<item>Shop owner</item>
<item>Taxi driver</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Eleanor, Buckitt, Wanda Abbott, shop owner},{Gareth, Parkes, Harry Lymes, taxi driver},{Julian, Lemming, Pat Thistle, designer},{Marlene, Dover, Sam Gomez, police office},{Oliver, Newton, R U O'Kaye, bar assistant}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="15" size="4x5" ordering="numeric" semantic = "">
<title>Snow Joke</title>
<text>
<preamble>Following a sudden, unexpected and unforecast blizzard the five residents of the village of Much-Creedens-in-the-Mett have found themselves unprepared to cope with a few inches of the winter white-stuff - no shovel, no salt, no grit. From the clues, can you work out each resident's address and the less-than-useful item they are using as a stand-in shovel to remove the snow from which part of their property?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The resident using a baking tray as a sort of shovel-cum-scoop to clear out their drive lives at a house numbered two higher than the one where some poor sap is trying to clear the path; the former of these isn't Fred Flatt-Foote, who isn't the person trying to clear away snow with a garden trowel.</clue>
<clue>Alan Abakk's only hope of clearing the snow at his home, which isn't 1 Addock Avenue, is a rather flimsy fish slice he's found in the kitchen drawer.</clue>
<clue>Percy Pansdown, who's trying to clear away the snow from his patio, lives at a number 1 higher than the person who is gamely, but ineffectually, shovelling with a ladel.</clue>
<clue>The children's plastic spade is being used at a lower-numbered house than the one where Norman Napping was caught napping but a higher-numbered house than the one whose back step is some way to being cleared.</clue>
<clue>Oliver Ofgard is clearing a step at a house numbered higher than the other resident clearing a step.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Resident">
<item>Alan Abakk</item>
<item>Fred Flatt-Foote</item>
<item>Norman Napping</item>
<item>Oliver Ofgard</item>
<item>Percy Pansdown</item>
</category>
<category name="Shovel">
<item>Baking tray</item>
<item>Fish slice</item>
<item>ladle</item>
<item>Plastic spade</item>
<item>Trowel</item>
</category>
<category name="Location">
<item>Back step</item>
<item>Drive</item>
<item>Front step</item>
<item>Path</item>
<item>Patio</item>
</category>
<category name="Address" keyword="numeric">
<item>1 Addock Avenue</item>
<item>2 Botchem Broadway</item>
<item>3 Cobbled Crescent</item>
<item>5 Makeshift Mews</item>
<item>6 Stopgap Street</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Alan Abakk, fish slice, path, 3 Cobbled Crescent},{Fred Flatt-Foote, ladle, back step, 1 Addock Avenue},{Norman Napping, baking tray, drive, 5 Makeshift mews},{Oliver Ofgard, trowel, front step, 6 Stopgap Street},{Percy Pansdown, plastic spade, patio, 2 Botchem Broadway}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="16" size="4x5" ordering="numeric" semantic = "scored" other = "preamble-info, sums">
<title>Duck!</title>
<text>
<preamble>The monthly darts tournament at the Broken Arrow public house in the Little Dublin area of Netherlipp is always a tense moment, for anyone else in the bar that is. The darts players at the Broken Arrow are, by popular estimation, the worst in the universe. But the players have been practising and in the first round of clues, can you say where each player's three darts ended up?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Much to his surprise, Boris Bung scored with his first dart and then hit the landlord's hat (actually a pith hemlet, the landlord's no idiot) with his second.</clue>
<clue>Harland Hurl's third dart made a satisfying 'thunk' as it hit the door to the snug; his second hadn't hit the pub bar.</clue>
<clue>Sylvester Sling's first dart hit a customer's book, which was fortunate as she was using it to cover her head at the time; he scored a lower number of points than the player whose dart ended up in a table.</clue>
<clue>The person whose dart hit the sign 'Gents' on a door just above the 'e' scored with his third dart.</clue>
<clue>The player who hit the window frame with their first dart and managed to hit the floor with their third wasn't Charlie Chuck.</clue>
<clue>The thrower who left the landlord hopping when his dart ended up in his shoe, didn't throw the next into the pub bar.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Thrower">
<item>Boris Bung</item>
<item>Charlie Chuck</item>
<item>Harland Hurl</item>
<item>Paul Pitch</item>
<item>Sylvester Sling</item>
</category>
<category name="First dart">
<item>Customer's book</item>
<item>Landlord's shoe</item>
<item>Scored 1</item>
<item>Scored 4</item>
<item>Window frame</item>
</category>
<category name="Second dart">
<item>Bar</item>
<item>Gents door</item>
<item>Landlord's hat</item>
<item>Table</item>
<item>scored 6</item>
</category>
<category name="Third dart">
<item>Chair</item>
<item>Floor</item>
<item>Scored 3</item>
<item>Scored 9</item>
<item>Snug door</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Boris Bung, scored 1, landlord's hat, chair},{Charlie Chuck, landlord's shoe, gents door, scored 9},{Harland Hurl, scored 4, table, snug door},{Paul Pitch, window frame, scored 6, floor},{Sylvester Sling, customer's book, bar, scored 3}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="17" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "">
<title> Riverside Pubs</title>
<text>
<preamble>This puzzle is about five pubs which can be found in the Keighshire countryside and which do a roaring trade in spring and summer by advertising the delights of their beer gardens which sit next to small brooks or streams, all of which are ambitiously named as rivers. From the clues, can you work out in whcih village each pub sits, the minimal watercourse it overlooks and the brewery, or none, which owns it and provides it with its ale?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The Convents Brewery owns the pub on the River Leke; this is neither The Horse and Hare nor the pub at Ayleham, through which village the River Dribbel dribbles.</clue>
<clue>Queens Brewery in netherlipp owns the pub at Mildford; this is not The Oak and Anchor.</clue>
<clue>The Rat and Hounds at Pilston is not the pub past which the River Ooze oozes.</clue>
<clue>The Crown and Penny is on the banks of the River Seap and The Horse and Hare, which is owned by Monks Brewery, is not the pub in the historic village of Bitterborn.</clue>
<clue>The Fox and Badger is a Free House and Bloomers brewery doesn't own The Oak and Anchor.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Pub">
<item>Crown and Penny</item>
<item>Fox and Badger</item>
<item>Horse and Hare</item>
<item>Oak and Anchor</item>
<item>Rat and Hounds</item>
</category>
<category name="Village">
<item>Ayleham</item>
<item>Bereburgh</item>
<item>Bitterborn</item>
<item>Mildford</item>
<item>Pilston</item>
</category>
<category name="River">
<item>Dribbel</item>
<item>Leke</item>
<item>Ooze</item>
<item>Seap</item>
<item>Trickel</item>
</category>
<category name="Brewery">
<item>Bloomers</item>
<item>Convents</item>
<item>Free House</item>
<item>Monks</item>
<item>Queens</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Rat and Hounds, Pilston, Trickel, Bloomers},{Oak and Anchor, Bitterborn, Leke, Convents},{Fox and Badger, Ayleham, Dribbel, Free House},{Crown and Penny, Mildford, Seap, Queens},{Horse and Hare, Bereburgh, Ooze, Monks}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="18" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "street layout">
<title>Cross Breeds</title>
<text>
<preamble>Five of the houses along Baskerville Lane have pet dogs and, following the trend to make specific cross breeds, each is a mixture of two flavours of dog. From the clues, can you work out the name of the family at each house (the numbers run conventionally with the odds on one side, the evens on the other and consecutive odds and evens being neighbours), the name they've applied to the new breed they've created and the regular visitor to the house that sends their pet into paroxysms of barking.</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The Hound family's pet, who likes to give the dustmen the full force of its bark, lives next door to the dallie dog (that's a blend of Dalmatian and collie).</clue>
<clue>The Pooch family, who live at 3 Baskerville Lane, don't live next door to the Kurrs.</clue>
<clue>The boxsky (an amalgamation of a boxer and a husky) inhabits 4 Baskerville Lane, which is on the opposite side of the road to the dog whose barking at the postman is legendary in canine circles.</clue>
<clue>The cross between a Labrador and a beagle - a beagrador (or I suppose they could have called it a labragle) - never lets the arrival of the window cleaner go unannounced but doesn't live with the Welp family; the spanoodle (a poodle merged with a spaniel) lives next door.</clue>
<clue>The Yappa family's pet is a cross between a great Dane and a greyhound - great hound sounded too generic, so they chose greydane.</clue>
<clue>The dog at 6 Baskerville Lane wakes early to 'greet' the milkman.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Number">
<item>1</item>
<item>3</item>
<item>4</item>
<item>6</item>
<item>8</item>
</category>
<category name="Surname">
<item>Hound</item>
<item>Kurr</item>
<item>Pooch</item>
<item>Welp</item>
<item>Yappa</item>
</category>
<category name="Breed">
<item>Beagrador</item>
<item>Boxsky</item>
<item>Dallie</item>
<item>Greydane</item>
<item>Spanoodle</item>
</category>
<category name="Visitor">
<item>Dustman</item>
<item>Meter reader</item>
<item>Milkman</item>
<item>Postman</item>
<item>Window cleaner</item>
</category>
<solution>{{1,Welp, spanoodle, postman},{3, Pooch, beagrador, window cleaner},{4, Hound, boxsky, dustman},{6, Kurr, dallie, milkman},{8, Yappa, greydane, meter reader}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="19" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "gender">
<title>Media Campaign</title>
<text>
<preamble>The editors of five Keighshire papers each called one of their cub reporters into their office and gave them a similar project. Each reporter was to become the paper's official social media correspondent (no, sadly, there was no extra remuneration involved) and to begin a virtual campaign for some cause or other that the paper could then use for promotional purposes. From the clues, can you say for which paper each reporter works, the social media network they chose and the subject of the campaign they started?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Gideon Gosseppe decided to play it safe and start a campaign for lower taxes.</clue>
<clue>Lydia Lybal left her editor's office and immediately began her campaign on the Myscope network.</clue>
<clue>Sylvia Slandar, who has worked for the 'Stonekeigh Advertiser' since leaving university last summer, wasn't' the reporter whose Double Summer Time campaign for daylight saving will mean more light in the morning... or is it the evening? - the details don't really matter - is gathering speed on Mugbook.</clue>
<clue>Seymour Scandell, who doesn't work for the 'Netherlipp Clarion', hasn't begun a campaign for more bank holidays.</clue>
<clue>The cub reporter for the 'Storbury Globe', who began their campaign on Youpipe, isn't Debbis De Fayme, who has never used the Chirrup social network.</clue>
<clue>The cub reporter for the 'Norchester Argus' is a woman, the reporter who started the campaign on the Pimport website is a man; the latter of these two isn't the 'Wallingfen Recorder' reporter who started a campaign to raise speed limits (or maybe lower them, they're waiting to see which way the wind blows).</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Reporter">
<item>Debbie De Fayme</item>
<item>Gideon Gosseppe</item>
<item>Lydia Lybal</item>
<item>Seymour Scandell</item>
<item>Sylvia Slandar</item>
</category>
<category name="Paper">
<item>Netherlipp Clarion</item>
<item>Northchester Argus</item>
<item>Stonekeigh Advertiser</item>
<item>Storbury Globe</item>
<item>Wallingfen Recorder</item>
</category>
<category name="Social Media">
<item>Chirrup</item>
<item>Mugbook</item>
<item>Myscope</item>
<item>Pimport</item>
<item>Youpipe</item>
</category>
<category name="Campaign">
<item>Bank hols</item>
<item>Daylight saving</item>
<item>Fuel prices</item>
<item>Speed limits</item>
<item>Taxes</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Debbie De Fayme, Northchester Argus, Mugbook, daylight saving}, {Gideon Gosseppe, Netherlipp Clarion, Pimport, taxes},{Lydia Lybal, Wallingfen Recorder, Myscope, speed limits},{Seymour Scandell, Storbury Globe, Youpipe, fuel prices},{Sylvia Slandar, Stonekeigh Advertiser, Chirrup, bank hols}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="20" size="4x5" ordering="word length" semantic = "">
<title>Sporting Drones</title>
<text>
<preamble>On a summer weekend, each of our friends from the Drones Club was invited to play one of his acquaintances at a sport at which he was by no means expert - which is, of course, why the other man, seeking an easy victory, chose to challenge him in the first place. From the clues, can you work out the name and occupation of the man who challenged each Drone, and the sport at which he comprehensively defeated him?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Gerald Huntington was challenged by Plum Fairfax, but not to a bout of the Japanese sport of kendo, which involves fighting with wooden swords and was hardly known in Britain in those days.</clue>
<clue>The Drone challenged to a round of golf by the Guards officer (regimental champion three years running) was not Archie Fotheringhay, whose invitation did not come from Bones Fitzfulke.</clue>
<clue>Montague Ffolliott's opponent was a banker by profession - but had represented Britain in his particular sport at the World Championships.</clue>
<clue>The man who challenged Rupert de Grey had a surname shorter than that of the one who took on a Drone with sabres in a fencing bout but one letter longer than that of the farmer - who was, of course, a "gentleman" farmer, not a working one.</clue>
<clue>Ernest Cherub Beckwith served in the Royal Navy during Work War I, but has never in the Guards.</clue>
<clue>Foxy Touchwood, who challenged one Drone to a game of real tennis (also known as royal tennis), was not the famous explorer and world traveller.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Drone">
<item>Archie Fotheringhay</item>
<item>Edward Tanqueray</item>
<item>Gerald Huntington</item>
<item>Montague Ffolliott</item>
<item>Rupert de Grey</item>
</category>
<category name="Challenger">
<item>Bones Fitzfulke</item>
<item>Caddy Lupton</item>
<item>Cherub Beckwith</item>
<item>Foxy Touchwood</item>
<item>Plum Fairfax</item>
</category>
<category name="Occupation">
<item>Banker</item>
<item>Car dealer</item>
<item>Explorer</item>
<item>Farmer</item>
<item>Guards officer</item>
</category>
<category name="Sport">
<item>Fencing</item>
<item>Golf</item>
<item>Kendo</item>
<item>Real tennis</item>
<item>Roller skating</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Archie Fotheringhay, Foxy Touchwood, car dealer, real tennis},{Edward Tanquerary, Caddy Lupton, Gurads officer, golf},{Gerald Huntington, Plum Fairfax, farmer, roller-skating},{Montague Ffolliott, Bones Fitzfulke, banker, fencing},{Rupert de Grey, Cherub Beckwith, explorer, kendo}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="21" size="4x5" ordering="currency" semantic = "" other="'Park' name/service part">
<title>Drop and shop</title>
<text>
<preamble>These five ladies from Netherlipp like nothing more than a good mooch around the shops but find that their retail therapy style can be a little cramped by their other responsibilities. To their rescue have come the five shopping centres they're visiting today who have created a drop zone where shoppers can leave things to be picked up later. From the clues, can you say which woman visited which mall, what encumbrance she left in the safe hands of the amll staff and the subsidised price they charge for the service?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Keighshire Hall has a Kidzone in which your little darlings can play while you shop; it costs £1 more than CarFinder that parks and retrieves your car, removing the need to remember where you left it.</clue>
<clue>Stephanie Seed uses the Park Your Pooch service to look after her pampered poodle; this isn't the most expensive service.</clue>
<clue>Stonekeigh Gardens' service costs £1 less than the one utilised by Laurinda Leeve, which is not the most expensive, but £1 more than the Bag Drop service where bulging and heavy shopping bags can be left for collection later.</clue>
<clue>The Hubby Hold - somewhere to leave grumpy husbands whilse the real business of shopping is done - is free; they're really not much trouble given a chair and sight of a TV.</clue>
<clue>River Centre's service is more expensive than the one chosen by Melissa Maroon; the service that costs £1 isn't at Netherlipp Mall.</clue>
<clue>Pauline Park always shops at the Northchester Northfield centre.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Shopping centre">
<item>Keighshire Hall</item>
<item>Netherlipp Mall</item>
<item>Stonekeigh Gardens</item>
<item>Northchester Northfield</item>
<item>River Centre</item>
</category>
<category name="Name">
<item>Daphne Ditch</item>
<item>Laurinda Leeve</item>
<item>Melissa Maroon</item>
<item>Pauline Park</item>
<item>Stephanie Seed</item>
</category>
<category name="Service">
<item>Bag Drop</item>
<item>CarFinder</item>
<item>Hubby Hold</item>
<item>Kidzone</item>
<item>Park Your Pooch</item>
</category>
<category name="Price">
<item>Free</item>
<item>£1</item>
<item>£2</item>
<item>£3</item>
<item>£4</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Keighshire Hall, Daphne Ditch, Kidzone, £4},{Netherlipp Mall, Melissa Maroon, Hubby Hold, free},{Stonekeigh Gardens, Stephanie Seed, park Your Pooch, £2},{Northchester Northfield, Pauline park, Bag Drop, £1},{River Centre, Laurinda Leeve, CarFinder, £3}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="22" size="4x5" ordering="alphabetic" semantic = "" other="alphabetic position">
<title>War in Print</title>
<text>
<preamble>At this year's Storbury Skirmish, the town's annual military hobby fair, there were five different stalls run by booksellers from various locations and specialising in books about different periods or aspects of military history. From the clues below, can you work out the name of each bookshop and stall, the person running it, where the stall is based and its speciality?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The bookstall based in Ipswich specialises in books about the two World Wars.</clue>
<clue>The Lincoln-based bookstall has a shorter name than the one run by Basil Clancy, which sells mainly books about the period of the Napoleonic Wars - Basil's the guy with his hat on sideways and one hand stuck in the front of this jacket.</clue>
<clue>Eric Fraser comes from bedford, which is also where the bookstall he's running is based; Gary Higgins has no connection with the stall which trades as Valiant Books.</clue>
<clue>Vikki Wren runs Steadfast Books, which doesn't go in for books about naval warfare.</clue>
<clue>Portcullis, whose stall is stocked with books about medieval warfare - everything from the conquests of Charlemagne to the Wars of the Roses - isn't based in Nottingham.</clue>
<clue>Kriegspiel Books of warwick don't employ Gary Higgins,</clue>
<clue>The stall which is stocked almost exclusively with books on military aviation has its base in a city whose name begins with a letter in the second half of the alphabet; it isn't called Dispatches - the stall, that is, not the city - although, of course, the city isn't either.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Stall">
<item>Dispatches</item>
<item>Kriegspiel</item>
<item>Portcullis</item>
<item>Standfast</item>
<item>Valiant</item>
</category>
<category name="Run by">
<item>Basil Clancy</item>
<item>Derek Cornwell</item>
<item>Eric Fraser</item>
<item>Gary Higgins</item>
<item>Vikki Wren</item>
</category>
<category name="Based in">
<item>Bedford</item>
<item>Ipswich</item>
<item>Lincoln</item>
<item>Nottingham</item>
<item>Warwick</item>
</category>
<category name="Speciality">
<item>Medieval period</item>
<item>Military aviation</item>
<item>Napoleonic period</item>
<item>Naval warfare</item>
<item>World wars</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Dispatches, Gary Higgins, Ipswich, World wars},{Kriegspiel, Basil Clancy, Warwick, Napoleonic period},{Portcullis, Eric Fraser, Bedford, Medieval period},{Standfast, Vikki Wren, Nottingham, Military aviation},{Valiant, Derek Cornwell, Lincoln, Naval warfare}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="23" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "">
<title>Keigh Battles</title>
<text>
<preamble>the history of Keighshire is not a particularly military or bloody one but it does contain a few skirmishes which are dignified with the title 'battle' whose dates and other particulars the schoolchildren of the county are forced to learn at an early age. From the clues, can you work out the year in which each military altercation took place together with the rank and name of the Keighshire hero of the day?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The Battle of Clodden - a small scrap in the Clodden Woods - did not take place in 1409.</clue>
<clue>The Battle of Dolsby Bay - Dolsby Bay is a bend on the River Keigh and the 'battle' was a brief fight between two retreating groups of soldiers - took place in 1466, but the hero was not Brigadier Quickley.</clue>
<clue>The hero of the Battle of Narwood is the Captain, who is not Dumbson; The soldier called Gummer was not the Major.</clue>
<clue>Blunda, who is not the General, was the noted hero - noted for his perfect timing of the phrases 'fall back', 'retreat' and 'run away' - at the Battle of Hayes Field, which did not take place in 1409.</clue>
<clue>The General featured in the battle which took place in 1798; the soldier called Compler was the hero of the 1530 incident.</clue>
<clue>The Battle of Dolsby Bay didn't feature Dumbson.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Battle">
<item>Clodden</item>
<item>Dolsby Bay</item>
<item>Edgeworth</item>
<item>Hayes Field</item>
<item>Narwood</item>
</category>
<category name="Rank">
<item>Brigadier</item>
<item>Captain</item>
<item>General</item>
<item>Major</item>
<item>Marshal</item>
</category>
<category name="Name">
<item>Blunda</item>
<item>Clomper</item>
<item>Dumbson</item>
<item>Gummer</item>
<item>Quickley</item>
</category>
<category name="Year">
<item>1409</item>
<item>1466</item>
<item>1530</item>
<item>1625</item>
<item>1798</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Clodden, General, Dumbson, 1798},{Dolsby Bay, Marshal, Gummer, 1466},{Edgeworth, Brigadier, Quickley, 1409},{Hayes Field, Major, Blunda, 1625},{Narwood, Captain, Clomper, 1530}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="24" size="4x6" ordering="numeric" semantic = "">
<title>Female Fishers</title>
<text>
<preamble>The members of the Storbury Ladies Angling Society, informally known as the Female Fishers, are having a day out at the Barrow Hill fishing lake, and are just about to begin the most exciting part of it, when they abandon piscatorial pursuits and enjoy lunch, something nice to drink and a good old chat. From the clues, can you fill in each woman's name and what she's eating and drinking for lunch?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Rose Shaw's position is marked by a number two higher than that which indicates the lady lunching on sausage rolls, who is not drinking black coffee.</clue>
<clue>Pam Owen, whose lunchtime sandwiches contain chicken with sage and onion stuffing, is seated in a position greater than three.</clue>
<clue>The beer drinker, who is occupying an odd-numbered position less than four, is not Kay James.</clue>
<clue>The position of the Female Fisher with the ham rolls is numbered two lower than that of her friend who is drinking onion soup.</clue>
<clue>Jill Keen, who doesn't eat cheese rolls because cheese gives her a headache, is in seat five, while Alma Budd, who is drinking mineral water, is in a position the number of which differs by three from that of the woman with the pork pie.</clue>
<clue>The woman in position four is eating salami sandwiches.</clue>
<clue>The cola drinker (she's got a two-litre bottle of the stuff) is in a position numbered one higher than Eva Dunn's; the woman with the flask of hot drinking chocolate is sat at a number higher than three.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Position">
<item>1</item>
<item>2</item>
<item>3</item>
<item>4</item>
<item>5</item>
<item>6</item>
</category>
<category name="Fisherwoman">
<item>Alma Budd</item>
<item>Eva Dunn</item>
<item>Jill Keen</item>
<item>Kay James</item>
<item>Pam Owen</item>
<item>Rose Shaw</item>
</category>
<category name="Food item">
<item>Cheese rolls</item>
<item>Chicken sandwiches</item>
<item>Ham rolls</item>
<item>Pork pie</item>
<item>Salami sandwiches</item>
<item>Sausage rolls</item>
</category>
<category name="Drink item">
<item>Beer</item>
<item>Black coffee</item>
<item>Chocolate</item>
<item>Cola</item>
<item>Mineral water</item>
<item>Onion soup</item>
</category>
<solution>{{1, Kay James, Cheese rolls, Black coffee},{2,Alma Budd, Sausage rolls, Mineral water},{3, Eva Dunn, Ham rolls, Beer},{4, Rose Shaw, Salami sandwiches, Cola},{5, Jill Keen, Pork pies, Onion soup},{6, Pam Owen, Chicken sandwiches, Chocolate}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="25" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "surname" other="universal constraint">
<title>Consulting Detectives</title>
<text>
<preamble>The most famous 'consulting detective' in Victorian and Edwardian London was, of course, Sherlock Holmes, but he was just the tip o fhte iceberg with a number of others plying their trade on the streets of the capital. From the clues given, can you work out where each of those listed had rooms, the name of his friend and chronicler and the name of his housekeeper?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>None of the detectives had a surname beginning with the same letter as their address.</clue>
<clue>Major Dunbar, formerly of the Royal Garrison Artillery, was assistant and confidante to the detective who employed Mrs Mounts as his housekeeper; the house she looks after is not in Weaver Street.</clue>
<clue>Mrs Naples was the housekeeper in Potter's Lane, which wasn't the home and office of Fancourt Cleland, whose housekeeper was not Mrs Baffin; the Cooper Street premises were not those belonging to Calvin Pleydell.</clue>
<clue>Commander Ridley, who once commanded the firgate HMS 'Geryon', worked with his friend Zachary Gwynn.</clue>
<clue>The Hon Alec geddes worked with the detective based in Cutler Street, who was not Mrs Walvis' employer; Selwyn Dumain's office was on the fround floor of number 21 Weaver Street and his apartment on the building's first floor.</clue>
<clue>Kingsley Wycliff's housekeeper Mrs Colwyn was with him for many years, but he never, ever, met Rabbi Siegel.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Detective">
<item>Calvin Pleydell</item>
<item>Fancourt Cleland</item>
<item>Kingsley Wycliff</item>
<item>Selwyn Dumain</item>
<item>Zachary Gwynn</item>
</category>
<category name="Address">
<item>Cooper Street</item>
<item>Cutler Street</item>
<item>Glazier Square</item>
<item>Potter's Lane</item>
<item>Weaver Street</item>
</category>
<category name="Chronicler">
<item>Commander Ridley</item>
<item>Hon Alec Geddes</item>
<item>Major Dunbar</item>
<item>Professor Hacker</item>
<item>Rabbi Siegel</item>
</category>
<category name="Housekeeper">
<item>Mrs Baffin</item>
<item>Mrs Colwyn</item>
<item>Mrs Mounts</item>
<item>Mrs Naples</item>
<item>Mrs Walvis</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Calvin Pleydell, Cutler Street, Hon Alec Geddes, Mrs Baffin},{Fancourt Cleland, Glazier Square, Major Dunbar, Mrs Mounts},{Kingsley Wycliff, Cooper Street, Professor Hacker, Mrs Colwyn},{Selwyn Dumain, Weaver Street, Rabbi Siegel, Mrs Walvis},{Zachary Gwynn, Potter's Lane, Commander Riley, Mrs Naples}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="26" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "demonyms" other="universal constraint in preamble, category title relevant">
<title>Five into Ten</title>
<text>
<preamble>In a decathlon tournament the ten events, competed for over two days, were won by five athletes, each one winning two events, though no athlete won more than one track event. Can you exercise your way through the clues and find out who won each event and what was their nationality? The events are listed in the order that they occur. (The track events are 100m, 110m hurdles, 400m and 1500m.)</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The high jump and the discus were won by the same man; this was not Plodden, who was visiting from the Bulgarian city of Varna.</clue>
<clue>Despite hitting almost every barrier Staminaskov won the 110m hurdles and the British competitor won the 1500 metres.</clue>
<clue>Burleigh won the long jump with a personal best leap and the Russian competitor, who is not Tuffan, surprised everyone, including himself and his coach, by winning a track event on the first day.</clue>
<clue>The German did not win the shot put and the winner of the javelin, who wasn't Gritt, did not prove to be the fastest man by winning the 100 metres dash.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Name">
<item>Burleigh</item>
<item>Britt</item>
<item>Ploddon</item>
<item>Staminaskov</item>
<item>Tuffan</item>
</category>
<category name="Country">
<item>Britain</item>
<item>Bulgaria</item>
<item>Germany</item>
<item>Russia</item>
<item>United States</item>
</category>
<category name="First day win">
<item>High jump</item>
<item>110 metre hurdles</item>
<item>1500 metres</item>
<item>Javelin</item>
<item>Pole vault</item>
</category>
<category name="Second day win">
<item>High jump</item>
<item>400 metres</item>
<item>Long jump</item>
<item>100 metres</item>
<item>Shot put</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Burleigh, Britain, Long jump, 1500 metres},{Gritt, Russia, 100 metres, Pole vault},{Ploddon, Bulgaria, 400 metres, Javelin},{Staminaskov, United States, Shot put, 110m hurdles},{Tuffan, Germany, High jump, Discus}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="27" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "gender" other="determine gender from pronouns near nonrelevant pronouns">
<title>Not What You Know...</title>
<text>
<preamble>Undeterred by their recent failures, some would say fiascos, the five members of the fundraising committee at St Martha's Church in Hunchester have decided it's time to call in personal favours. Luckily each has a famous acquaintance and having plucked up the nerve to ring and ask them to attend an event they discovered that each celebrity had a reason for not being able to attend. From the clues, can you name each committee member's famous friend, their field of fame and reason for not being able to attend?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The junior government minister declined the invitation of one fundraiser because they had a date with a judge in a court on charges of....no, we don't need to go into that now.</clue>
<clue>Richard was at school for a year with the person who has made a big name for themselves as an opinionated newspaper columnist; this isn't Delia Benn.</clue>
<clue>Kate Gill, who is regularly titled Keighshire's own supermodel in the local press, isn't the acquaintance of Sean; Simon's old friend from university is Lenny Moss.</clue>
<clue>When Veronica rang her famous acquantaince she managed to speak only to his wife who said that owing to some legal mix-up her husband was spending a few months at Her Majesty's pleasure in the Keighshire Moor minimum security prison.</clue>
<clue>Tony Bruce, it turns out, has been in rehab for some addiction or other for the past few weeks and won't be back in circulation for some time.</clue>
<clue>The female TV chef isn't the celebrity who can't enter the country for a few months for tax reasons, living as they are on the Cashaway Islands tax haven.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Fundraiser">
<item>Louise</item>
<item>Richard</item>
<item>Sean</item>
<item>Simon</item>
<item>Veronica</item>
</category>
<category name="Famous friend">
<item>AA Smith</item>
<item>Delia Benn</item>
<item>Kate Gill</item>
<item>Lenny Moss</item>
<item>Tony Bruce</item>
</category>
<category name="Field">
<item>Columnist</item>
<item>Comedian</item>
<item>Government minister</item>
<item>Supermodel</item>
<item>TV chef</item>
</category>
<category name="Reason">
<item>In court</item>
<item>In prison</item>
<item>In rehab</item>
<item>On holiday</item>
<item>Tax exile</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Louise, Kate Gill, Supermodel, Tax exile},{Richard, Tony Bruce, columnist, Iin rehab},{Sean, Delia Benn, TV chef, On holiday},{Simon, Lenny Moss, Government Minister, In court},{Veronica, AA Smith, Comedian, In prison}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="28" size="4x5" ordering="years" semantic = "" other="years difference">
<title>Scandal at the Castle</title>
<text>
<preamble>Last year, there was a major scandal at Dansburgh Castle, the medieval fortress that is Eastshire's biggest tourist attraction. Five of the exhibits in the Castle Museum, supposedly found on the site in the past year, proved to have been discovered years earlier and miles away, and purchased by site director Reynard Fox. From the clues, can you work out where in the castle each exhibit was supposedly found and when and where it was actually unearthed?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The exhibit actually discovered in 1994 was claimed by the Castle Museum as a find from Lady Anne's Tower which had probably been handled by the famous Lady Anne Dubourg herself.</clue>
<clue>The magnificent jewel-encrusted knife described as having been discovered in the gatehouse of Dansburgh Castle was actually found eleven years after the exhibit which proved to have been found not in Eastshire but in one of the city gates of Canterbury, Kent.</clue>
<clue>The beautiful silver goblet decorated with the coat of arms of King Richard II was actually found in the ruins of Rievaulx Abbey in North Yorkshire; its discovery did not take place in 1950.</clue>
<clue>The wine jar, identified by its seal as the one-time receptable of a fine French-made wine, was actually discovered eleven years after the one supposedly found in Dansburgh's keep.</clue>
<clue>The copper bowl, 'positively identified' by Mr Fox's experts as the one time property of Lord Theodoric de Danisburg, which was not described as a find from the castle chapel, was discovered in 1961.</clue>
<clue>One of the exhibits was discovered not at Dansburgh but at Framlingham Castle, Suffolk, in 1972.</clue>
<clue>The item found during an excavation of a section of the city walls at York was not the knight's helmet.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Exhibit">
<item>Bowl</item>
<item>Goblet</item>
<item>Helmet</item>
<item>Knife</item>
<item>Wine jar</item>
</category>
<category name="Found">
<item>Chapel</item>
<item>Gatehouse</item>
<item>Keep</item>
<item>Lady Anne's Tower</item>
<item>South Tower</item>
</category>
<category name="Date">
<item>1950</item>
<item>1961</item>
<item>1972</item>
<item>1983</item>
<item>1994</item>
</category>
<category name="Location">
<item>Canterbury city gate</item>
<item>Framlingham Castle</item>
<item>Rievaulx Abbey</item>
<item>Warwick Castle</item>
<item>York city walls</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Bowl, South Tower, 1961, Canterbury city gate},{Goblet, Keep, 1983, Rievaulx Abbey},{Helmet, Chapel, 1950, Warwick Castle},{Knife, Gatehouse, 1972, Framlingham castle},{Wine jar, Lady Anne's Tower, 1994, York city walls}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="29" size="4x5" ordering="dates" semantic = "" other = "dates difference">
<title>Near Misses</title>
<text>
<preamble>The Perrill family took a fortnight's 'staycation' in Westshire last year and had a really good time - despite five narrow escapes from death and/or disaster. From the clues given, can you work out which beach they were visiting on each of the listed days, which family member had chosen it and what happened there?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>It was Mum's idea to visit the famous Dawcombe beach, where the Perills went two days after being showered with water - but nothing worse - by the explosion of a wartime sea mine which had drifted inshore.</clue>
<clue>Two days before the Perills had to be rescued by the inshore lifeboat when the motor launch 'Skylark' in which they were taking a trip round the bay ran aground on rocks, they went to Ottercross; two days after their 'shipwreck' they visited the beach resort selected by Glenda, the youngest of the family.</clue>
<clue>On the 7th, the family were nearly hit by a glider making a crash-landing, which passed a few metres above their heads before ploughing into the sand; this did not occur at Saltingham.</clue>
<clue>At Maidenstone, the Perills, enjoying their picnic lunch, narrowly avoided being hit by a landslide from the cliffs; Maidenstone wasn't selected by either Keith or Nigel.</clue>
<clue>Keith selected the beach visited on the 11th.</clue>
<clue>It was at the beach selected by Maurice Perill - known to his kids and in this problem as 'Dad' - that a car crashed off the promenade and onto the sands almost - but not quite - exactly where the family were sunbathing.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Date">
<item>7th</item>
<item>9th</item>
<item>11th</item>
<item>13th</item>
<item>15th</item>
</category>
<category name="Beach">
<item>Dawcombe</item>
<item>Kingsands</item>
<item>Maidenstone</item>
<item>Ottercross</item>
<item>Saltingham</item>
</category>
<category name="Chosen by">
<item>Dad</item>
<item>Glenda</item>
<item>Keith</item>
<item>Mum</item>
<item>Nigel</item>
</category>
<category name="Incident">
<item>Boat ran aground</item>
<item>Car crashed onto beach</item>
<item>Glider landing</item>
<item>Landslide</item>
<item>Mine explosion</item>
</category>
<solution>{{7th Kingslands, Nigel, Glider landing},{9th, Saltingham, Dad, Car crashed onto beach},{11th, Ottercross, Keith, Mine explosion},{13th Dawcombe, Mum, Boat ran aground},{15th, Maidenstone, Glenda, Landslide}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="30" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "gender, gendered professions" other="'dognapping' from 'dog'">
<title>Witness</title>
<text>
<preamble>Winters in the Californian town of San Angelo come suddenly, linger only in passing and move on before you can kick the snow from your shoes. Our five private eye friends are each out in the snow looking for a key witness who could shed some advantageous light on the actions of wealthy clients charged with varying misdemeanours. From the clues, can you name each detective's client, the crime with which they are charged and the identity of the witness who could clear their name?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Spike Spanner has been engaged by a wealthy woman charged with stealing something; Mike Mallet is walking the snowy streets of San Angelo on the trail of a female witness.</clue>
<clue>The man charged with stealing his neighbour's prize-winning poodle has engaged a private eye to track down a delivery boy who can apparently testify that the dog moved home of its own accord; this detective wasn't Ricky Wrench who wasn't employed by Lucinda Loded who is staring down the barrel of a jaywalking rap.</clue>
<clue>The witness Nicky Nail was searching for on behald of Wanda Well-Ealled, who wan't accused of vandalism, wasn't the barman.</clue>
<clue>Ricardo Richman didn't engage the services of Dick Drill.</clue>
<clue>Felicity Flush, whose innocence could apparently be proven by the testimony of a truck friver, wasn't the client accused of shoplifting; the alleged shoplifter hasn't asked their detective to find a newspaper seller.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Private eye">
<item>Dick Drill</item>
<item>Mike Mallet</item>
<item>Nicky Nail</item>
<item>Ricky Wrench</item>
<item>Spike Spanner</item>
</category>
<category name="Client">
<item>Felicity Flush</item>
<item>Lucinda Cloded</item>
<item>Riccardo Richman</item>
<item>Wanda Well-Ealled</item>
<item>Wesley Welth</item>
</category>
<category name="Crime">
<item>Car theft</item>
<item>Dognapping</item>
<item>Jaywalking</item>
<item>Shoplifting</item>
<item>Vandalism</item>
</category>
<category name="Witness">
<item>Barman</item>
<item>Delivery Boy</item>
<item>Newspaper seller</item>
<item>Tramp</item>
<item>Truck Driver</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Dick Drill, Wesley Welth, Dognapping, Delivery boy},{Make Mallet, Lucinda Loded, Jaywalking, Newspaper seller},{Nicky Nail, Wanda Well-Ealled, Shoplifting, Tramp},{Ricky Wrench, Ricardo Richman, Vandalism, Barman},{Spike Spanner, Felicity Flush, Car theft, Truck driver}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="31" size="6x4" ordering="" semantic = "">
<title>Picture Post</title>
<text>
<preamble>This week four Keighshire newspapers featured on their front pages photos of four celebrities or dignitaries snapped by keen and eager members of the public at nightclubs. From the clues, can you discover the name and occupation of the person whose picture appears in each paper, the name of the person who took the picture on their phone, the name of the nightclub and the word the newspaper used to describe the action being shown?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Neither of the pictures taken by female photographers were of female subjects.</clue>
<clue>Roger Rector appeared in glorious colour on the front of the 'Northchester Argus'.</clue>
<clue>The vicar was, according to the caption under the picture 'gyrating', when they were actually swerving out of the way of a flying bottle, having been called by the management to help negotiate between two warring factions across the dance floor.</clue>
<clue>The 'Netherlipp Clarion', being an old-fashioned sort of publication, chose the delightfully old-fashioned word 'canoodling' to describe their photo's contents.</clue>
<clue>The picture of Olivia O'Nair snapped by a mobile phone at Tramps Nightclub in Netherlipp High Street wasn't printed in the 'Keighshire Tribune'; Sam Slide took his photo in Drifters Nightclub just off Markey Square.</clue>
<clue>The photo under which the caption read 'slumper in the corner at Hobos Club' was not the one that featured the leader of Netherlipp council, who perhaps strangely in these circumstances, isn't called Chester Chambers, who also wasn't the person slumped in Hobos.</clue>
<clue>The photo of the footballer on the front of the 'Stonekeigh Advertiser' wasn't snapped by Cheryl Shutter.</clue>
<clue>The photo at Vagrants Nightclub wasn't taken by Cheryl Shutter; Sandra Socker, perhaps strangely in these circumstances, isn't the footballer, who wasn't the subject of the snap by Sid Snappe.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Newspaper">
<item>Keighshire Tibune</item>
<item>Netherlipp Clarion</item>
<item>Northchester Argus</item>
<item>Stonekeigh Advertiser</item>
</category>
<category name="Subject">
<item>Chester Chambers</item>
<item>Olivia O'Nair</item>
<item>Roger Rector</item>
<item>Sandra Socker</item>
</category>
<category name="Occupation">
<item>Council leader</item>
<item>Footballer</item>
<item>Radio DJ</item>
<item>Vicar</item>
</category>
<category name="Photographer">
<item>Cheryl Shutter</item>
<item>Sam Slide</item>
<item>Sharon Shoot</item>
<item>Sid Snappe</item>
</category>
<category name="Nightclub">
<item>Drifters</item>
<item>Hobos</item>
<item>Tramps</item>
<item>Vagrants</item>
</category>
<category name="Action">
<item>Canoodling</item>
<item>Cavorting</item>
<item>Gyrating</item>
<item>Slumped</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Keighshire Tribune, Sandra Socker, Vicar, Sam Slide, Drifters, Gyrating}, {Netherlipp Clarion, Olivia O'Nair, Council leader, Sid Snappe, Tramps, canoodling},{Northchester Argus, Roger Rector, Radio DJ, Cheryl Shutter, Hobos, Slumped},{Stonekeigh Advertiser, Chester Chambers, Footballer, Sharon Shoot, Vagrants, Cavorting}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="32" size="4x6" ordering="left-right" semantic = "" other="universal constraint, sums">
<title>Dress for Hire</title>
<text>
<preamble>Sphagnum Sisters dress hire shop in Netherlipp High Street has been providing formal wear for the residents of Keighshire ever since Sybil Sphagnum began the business in 1928. This week the shop window display comprises mannequins displaying three dinner jackets and three evening gowns. From the clues, can you name the style name of each jacket or dress, its colour and the price charged for one night's hire?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The three jackets are items 1, 3 and 6.</clue>
<clue>To hire the Ascot jacket and dress number 5 will cost �150 a night; the cost for the hire of jacket number 1 and the purple dress is a very reasonable �130.</clue>
<clue>The Wimbledon item, which isn't jacket 3, is hired out for �80 a night and the red garment costs �75 to hire for one night.</clue>
<clue>The Henley styled item, which is shown immediately to the left of a dress, has a hire charge of �5 lower than the green garment and �5 higher than dress 4; the green garment is shown somewhere to the right of the least expensive item to hire and dress 4 isn't the Proms styled item, which doesn't hire out at �65 a night.</clue>
<clue>The Cheltenham styled item is a jet black; jacket number 6 is a deep navy blue.</clue>
<clue>The grey garment is positioned to the immediate right of the one that costs �70 to hire.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Item">
<item>1</item>
<item>2</item>
<item>3</item>
<item>4</item>
<item>5</item>
<item>6</item>
</category>
<category name="Style Name">
<item>Ascot</item>
<item>Cheltenham</item>
<item>Glydenbourne</item>
<item>Henley</item>
<item>Proms</item>
<item>Wembley</item>
</category>
<category name="Colour">
<item>Black</item>
<item>Green</item>
<item>Grey</item>
<item>Purple</item>
<item>Navy blue</item>
<item>Red</item>
</category>
<category name="Cost">
<item>�60</item>
<item>�65</item>
<item>�70</item>
<item>�75</item>
<item>�80</item>
<item>�85</item>
</category>
<solution>{{1, Cheltenham, Black, �60},{2,Wimbledon, Green, �80},{3, Henley, Red, �75},{4, Glyndenbourne, Purple, �70},{5, Proms, Grey, �85},{6, Ascot, Navy blue, �65}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="33" size="4x5" ordering="years" semantic = "years difference">
<title>Dramatics</title>
<text>
<preamble>For the past five years, the annual Eddsbury Festival of Art and Culture has been held in February in the Eddsbury Town Hall and various other locations around town, and has included a competition for best new drama written by a local dramatist. From the clues, can you work out the writer and title of each year's winning play and what it is about?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The murder mystery 'Huffman', based on a real-life case from teh 1920s, took the silver Lady Vargrave trophy awarded to the winning entry the year before it went to Nigel Orton.</clue>
<clue>Isaac Jonson took the trophy the year after it went to a play about the plight of a homeless man living on the streets of Eddsbury, written by someone who lives in a Georgian mansion valued at �800,000.</clue>
<clue>In 2012, the prize went to a rather bleak and decidely unfunny 'comedy' called 'Midnight'.</clue>
<clue>'The Lights Went out' and the play about local politics in the 1940s won the prize two years apart - though not necessarily in that order.</clue>
<clue>In 2010, Rachel Shaw's play won, prompting some people to compain that it had only won because she was a woman and others to protest because her uncle was a borough councillor and a member of the selection committee.</clue>
<clue>Bruce Congreve's 'Lost Causes' won the trophy some years before the play about corruption in sport, which was specifically concerned with Eddsbury Rover's 21-0 loss to Grantchester United and a betting slip found in the glove compartment of the Manager's car.</clue>
<clue>In 2011, the winning play dealt with green issues.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Year">
<item>2009</item>
<item>2010</item>
<item>2011</item>
<item>2012</item>
<item>2013</item>
</category>
<category name="Writer">
<item>Bruce Congreve</item>
<item>Isaac Jonson</item>
<item>Nigel Orton</item>
<item>Rachel Shaw</item>
<item>Zoe Ayckbourn</item>
</category>
<category name="Play">
<item>Huffman</item>
<item>Inner Circle</item>
<item>Lost Causes</item>
<item>Midnight</item>
<item>The Lights Went Out</item>
</category>
<category name="Subject">
<item>Corruption in sport</item>
<item>Green issues</item>
<item>Homeless man</item>
<item>Local politics in 1940s</item>
<item>Murder Mystery</item>
</category>
<solution>{{2009, Bruce Congreve, Lost Causes, Local politics in 1940s},{2010, Rachel Shaw, Hufman, Murder mystery},{2011, Nigel Orton, The Lights Went Out, Green issues},{2012, Zoe Ayckbourn, Midnight, Homeless Man},{2013, Isaac Jonson, Inner Circle, Corruption in sport}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="34" size="4x5" ordering="months" semantic = "">
<title>Batting Partners</title>
<text>
<preamble>Springfield University is sending out five expeditions to study different bat species around the world. Each expedition will include a chiroptologist (bat expert) and a speleologist (cave expert), and each will take place in a different country. Match each team to their expedition and the month in which they'll be leaving.</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Paula's expedition will leave 1 month before Ruben's expedition.</clue>
<clue>Leona's team will leave 2 months after Spencer's team.</clue>
<clue>The team going to Nepal will leave 2 months after the team going to Angola.</clue>
<clue>Ruben's expedition will leave 1 month before Amelia's expedition.</clue>
<clue>Evan's expedition will leave sometime before Horace's expedition.</clue>
<clue>Leon's team will be going to Turkmenistan.</clue>
<clue>Spencer's team will leave 1 month before the expedition going to Iran.</clue>
<clue>Of the expedition leaving in July and Kay's team, one will be going to Belize and the other will include Spencer.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Month">
<item>April</item>
<item>May</item>
<item>June</item>
<item>July</item>
<item>August</item>
</category>
<category name="Chiroptologist">
<item>Evan</item>
<item>Horace</item>
<item>Leon</item>
<item>Ruben</item>
<item>Spencer</item>
</category>
<category name="Speleologist">
<item>Amelia</item>
<item>Kay</item>
<item>Leona</item>
<item>Paula</item>
<item>Ronda</item>
</category>
<category name="Country">
<item>Angola</item>
<item>Belize</item>
<item>Iran</item>
<item>Nepal</item>
<item>Turkmenistan</item>
</category>
<solution>{{April,Spencer,Kay,Angola},{May,Evan,Paula,Iran},{June,Ruben,Leona,Nepal},{July,Horace,Amelia,Belize},{August,Leon,Ronda,Turkmenistan}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="35" size="4x3" ordering="" semantic = "">
<title>Ticket to Ride</title>
<text>
<preamble>Last week, three people who regularly need to visit the city travelled by train and tube to reach their destinations. Unfortunately for each of them, the underground system failed them and each spent half an hour or so stuck in a tunnel between two stations. From the clues, can you say which person was stuck between which two stations and the reason given for the hold-up?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Breandan Buss' tube train had just pulled out of Oxford Square when it ground to a halt; Thomas Tramme's train came to a jolting stop a few hundred yards before getting to Leicester Bridge.</clue>
<clue>Fenella Ferry and her fellow stranded passengers should have been told that the delay was caused by a malfunction in the tannoy system but weren't because of a malfunction in the Tannoy system.</clue>
<clue>The hold-up just before Waterloo Arch wasn't caused by a wi-fi failure.</clue>
<clue>One train sat inert for almost half an hour between Knights Station and Fleet Circus.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Name">
<item>Brendan Buss</item>
<item>Fenella Ferry</item>
<item>Thomas Tramme</item>
</category>
<category name="From">
<item>Knights Square</item>
<item>Marble Street</item>
<item>Oxford Square</item>
</category>
<category name="To">
<item>Fleet Circus</item>
<item>Leicester Bridge</item>
<item>Waterloo Arch</item>
</category>
<category name="Reason">
<item>Litter on line</item>
<item>Tannoy malfunction</item>
<item>Wi-fi failure</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Brenda Buss, Oxford Square, Waterloo Arch, Litter on line},{Fenella Ferry, Knights Station, Fleet Circus, Tannoy malfunction},{Thomas Tramme, Marble Street, Leicester Bridge, Wi-fi failure}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="36" size="4x3" ordering="currency" semantic = "">
<title>I Feel Fine</title>
<text>
<preamble>After last week's transport problems, the three city-goers have this week chosen to drive themselves to their appointments in town. But things didn't go too well and, having found places to leave their cars, they transgressed a parking law and found a fine attached to their windscreen when they returned. From the clues, can you say near which city landmark each parked, which law they broke and how much they were fined?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Parking outside the cathedral is for one hour only - someone stayed too long.</clue>
<clue>Fenella Ferry left her car outside the museum.</clue>
<clue>Thomas parked his car in a pay-and-display space, did neither and received a fine; he wasn't charged the largest amount.</clue>
<clue>Brendan Buss was fined half as much as the person who parked in the restricted parking zone.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Name">
<item>Brendan Buss</item>
<item>Fenella Ferry</item>
<item>Thomas Tramme</item>
</category>
<category name="Location">
<item>Cathedral</item>
<item>City Hall</item>
<item>Museum</item>
</category>
<category name="Law">
<item>One hour parking</item>
<item>Pay and display</item>
<item>Restricted parking</item>
</category>
<category name="Fine">
<item>�10</item>
<item>�20</item>
<item>�40</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Brendan Buss, cathedral, One-hour parking, �20},{Fenella Ferry, Museum, Restricted parking, �40},{Thomas Tramme, City Hall, Pay and Display, �10}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="37" size="4x4" ordering="ordinals" semantic = "Head of queue">
<title>Quarrelling</title>
<text>
<preamble>Four young and recently married couples are each in their car driving to town from their homes in Paradise Avenue for a day's work and each couple is currently in the middle of a small argument that has the potential to blow up out of all proportion. They have pulled up in line at the lights and the bickering has started again. From the clues, can you name the woman and man in each of the cars in first to fourth position in the queue and say what it is they are squabbling about?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Amelia has pulled up directly behind the car in which Wayne is sitting in the passenger seat and directly ahead of the one in which the occupants can't agree on which movie to see tonight - one of them wants to see 'Alien Death Machines from Outer Space' while her husband prefers 'Girls Night Out - The Musical'.</clue>
<clue>Bernice, who isn't in the car at the head of the queue, is telling her husband that it's his turn to pick up the milk; she knows for sure because it's always turn.</clue>
<clue>Chloe and Zachary are sat in their car not speaking - except to bicker that is.</clue>
<clue>Xavier is in the car third in line.</clue>
<clue>Yves, who is not the man who wants to paint the hall in Evening Breeze while his new wife is insisting on Twilight Zephyr, isn't in thr fourth car in line.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Position">
<item>First</item>
<item>Second</item>
<item>Third</item>
<item>Fourth</item>
</category>
<category name="Woman">
<item>Amelia</item>
<item>Bernice</item>
<item>Chloe</item>
<item>Denise</item>
</category>
<category name="Man">
<item>Wayne</item>
<item>Xavier</item>
<item>Yves</item>
<item>Zachary</item>
</category>
<category name="Quarrel">
<item>Buy milk</item>
<item>Hall colour</item>
<item>Hoiday plans</item>
<item>Movie choice</item>
</category>
<solution>{{First, Denise, Yves, Holiday plans},{Second, Bernice, Wayne, Buy milk},{Third, Amelia, Xavier, Hall colour},{Fourth, Chloe, Zachary, Movie choice}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="38" size="4x4" ordering="" semantic = "">
<title>Quarantine!</title>
<text>
<preamble>Dormitory B4 of St Keigh's Boarding School is out of bounds to anyone except the school matron and its four occupants as each of the boarders has come down with a bad cold. They've spent an enjoyable day ganging up in various permutations of three and beating up the other for infecting the dormitory in the first place, but they're bored with that and are currently sat in bed sipping home-made remedies sent in by their mothers. From the clues, can you say which lad is sipping which drink, the hat he's wearing after matron said they should keep their heads warm and the piece of homework they are delighted to be dodging by being ill?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Chris Cockcroft is wearing a balaclava; actually it's an overlarge rugby sock with a hole cut in it, but beggars can't be choosers.</clue>
<clue>The lad in the Netherlipp Rovers bobble hat is sipping a mug of hot lemon; it's not Hamish Hazel who is sniffing suspiciously and trying to drink a mug of steaming honey and lime.</clue>
<clue>The lad trying to drink his ginger tea is avoiding a Latin translation and Ben Barton, who is happy to be dodging a particularly tricky maths assignment, isn't the lad in his school cap.</clue>
<clue>The lad wearing his rugby scrumcap (and boxing gloves, just to be on the safe side) is dodging writing a history essay.</clue>
<clue>Martin Master's mother swears by rosehip tea and has sent a batch for her son to sip.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Boy">
<item>Barton</item>
<item>Cockcroft</item>
<item>Hazel</item>
<item>Masters</item>
</category>
<category name="Drink">
<item>Ginger tea</item>
<item>Honey and lime</item>
<item>Hot lemon</item>
<item>Rosehip tea</item>
</category>
<category name="Hat">
<item>English</item>
<item>History</item>
<item>Latin</item>
<item>Maths</item>
</category>
<category name="Homework">
<item>Balaclava</item>
<item>Bobble hat</item>
<item>School cap</item>
<item>scrumcap</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Barton, Hot lemon, Bobble hat, Maths},{Cockcroft, Honey and lime, Balaclave, english},{Hazel, Ginger tea, School cap, Latin},{Masters, Rosehip tea, Scrumcap, History}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="39" size="4x4" ordering="" semantic = "">
<title>Quartermaster</title>
<text>
<preamble>Four agents from the ultra-secret MI99 division have visited the department's quartermaster to collect a gadget for their latest assignment. From the clues, can you work out to which exotic island each agent is being sent, what item their new piece of equipment is disguied and its ingenious secret?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>One agent was given a new wallet which they were assured was bulletproof - all they need to do now is persuade the baddies to aim at it.</clue>
<clue>Jane Fuse has been given an assignment on Mauritius; her gadget won't explode, not unless she straps it to a stick of dynamite, that is.</clue>
<clue>Jon Stick will need to visit the medical wing of MI99 before heading to the airport after shooting himself in thr foot when trying out his new laser device; he won't be catching the plane to Tahiti.</clue>
<clue>The agent holding the air ticket for Bermuda, who isn;t Jack Fix, has been given a new and rather smart looking fountain pen.</clue>
<clue>The agent heading for the long-haul flight to Bali has been given an item that can create a smokescrenn should the need arise; this isn't the very normal-looking mobile phone.</clue>
<clue>Jack Fix's visit to the quartermaster didn't result in his leaving with a new watch.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Agent">
<item>Jack Fix</item>
<item>Jane Fuse</item>
<item>Joan Link</item>
<item>Jon Stick</item>
</category>
<category name="Island">
<item>Bali</item>
<item>Bermuda</item>
<item>Mauritius</item>
<item>Tahiti</item>
</category>
<category name="Item">
<item>Bulletproof</item>
<item>Explosive</item>
<item>Laser</item>
<item>Smoke</item>
</category>
<category name="Gadget">
<item>Pen</item>
<item>Phone</item>
<item>Wallet</item>
<item>Watch</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Jack Fix, Tahiti, Mobile phone, Explosive},{Jane Fuse, Mauritius, Wallet, Bullet proof},{Joan Link, Ball, Watch, Smoke},{Jon Stick, Bermuda, Pen, Laser}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="40" size="4x4" ordering="" semantic = "">
<title>Q Villains</title>
<text>
<preamble>Four agents from the ultra-secret MI99 division have found themselves being held prisoner by the dastardly leader of the dastardly organisation they were sent to defeat. From these clues below, can you work out the name of each agent's foe, the gist of his evil plan and the way in which our heroes and heroines eventually made their dramatic escape?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Jack Fix has encountered a deranged character who has plans to become World President.</clue>
<clue>Jon Stick was the agent who made a dramatic escape on a hang glider but he wasn't escaping from the evil mind known as the Quarry.</clue>
<clue>Joan Link activated her high-tech gadget and, with the ensuing smokescreen causing mayhem all around, escaped the clutches of the evil Quisling and his evil band.</clue>
<clue>The Quill had demanded a trillion euro ransom lest he do something really quite dastardly; The Quasar stood on the beach and watched as his erstwhile prisoner disappeared towards the horizon on board a kite surfer.</clue>
<clue>Jane Fuse did not encounter the villain whose aim was the total destruction of the UK; the villain hoping to forment a world war was not the one from which an agent escaped astride a jetski or kite surfer.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Agent">
<item>Jack Fix</item>
<item>Jane Fuse</item>
<item>Joan Link</item>
<item>Jon Stick</item>
</category>
<category name="Villain">
<item>The Quarry</item>
<item>The Quasar</item>
<item>The Quill</item>
<item>The Quisling</item>
</category>
<category name="Plan">
<item>Ransom</item>
<item>UK Destruction</item>
<item>World President</item>
<item>World war</item>
</category>
<category name="Escape">
<item>Hang glider</item>
<item>Hovercraft</item>
<item>Jetski</item>
<item>Kite surfer</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Jack Fix, The Quasar, World President, Kite surfer},{Jane Fuse, The Quarry, World war, Hovercraft},{Joan Link, The Quisling, UK destruction, Jetski},{Jon Stick, The Quill, Ransom, Hang glider}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="41" size="4x5" ordering="months" semantic = "">
<title>That Horrible Woman</title>
<text>
<preamble>Helen Wheels is a film actress who specialises in playing cruel, ruthless and completely unpleasant middle-aged women (though she is actually a charming and kind person), and appeared in five movies released last year. From the clues, can you work out the details of her participation in each month's release - the name and role of her character and the title of the film?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>The April release, which wasn't the romantic comedy 'Playing Away', featured Helen as Freda Grimm.</clue>
<clue>In the comedy thriller 'The High Life', Helen played a demented right-wing terrorist leader, whose name was not Ilsa Harsch.</clue>
<clue>The August release in which Helen played a sadistic teacher at a school for teenage girls, wasn't the crime thriller 'Frame', in which she appeared as Dora Flint.</clue>
<clue>It wasn't the June release in which Helen played a highly biased and untrustworthy County Court judge.</clue>
<clue>Helen took the role of unbalanced psychiatrist Dr Roxana Stern in the film released two months before the one in which she played the central character's mother-in-law.</clue>
<clue>The horror film 'In the Forest' came out in February.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Month">
<item>February</item>
<item>April</item>
<item>June</item>
<item>August</item>
<item>October</item>
</category>
<category name="Character name">
<item>Dora Flint</item>
<item>Freda Grimm</item>
<item>Ilsa Harsch</item>
<item>Norah Leather</item>
<item>Roxana Stern</item>
</category>
<category name="Character Role">
<item>Judge</item>
<item>Mother-in-law</item>
<item>Psychiatrist</item>
<item>Teacher</item>
<item>Terrorist</item>
</category>
<category name="Title">
<item>Cutting Edge</item>
<item>Frame</item>
<item>In the Forest</item>
<item>Playing Away</item>
<item>The High Life</item>
</category>
<solution>{{February, Roxana Stern, Pyschiatrist, In the Forest},{April, Freda Grimm, Mother-in-law, Cutting Edge},{June, Noral Leather, Terrorist, The High Life},{August, L=Ilsa Harsch, Teacher, Playing Away},{October, Dora Flint, Judge, Frame}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="42" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "gender">
<title>Not Born in the USA</title>
<text>
<preamble>Did you knwo that American tennis player John McEnroe was actually born in West Germany? Or that US actress Victoria Principal (remember her in 'Dallas'?) was born in Japan? The five celebrities listed below are less well-known, but are also American citizens born, of American parentage, outside the USA; from the clues given, can you work out each one's full name and occcupation and where they were born?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Nancy Portland is not a golfer - in fact she's never even picked up a golf club.</clue>
<clue>Luke was born in Spain, where his father was based with the USAF; the sprinter, whose surname is Fairbanks, wasn't born in Australia.</clue>
<clue>Bernie, who isn't the lady born in Thailand, is a talk show host, though only on daytime TV; Ms Troy was once one of Bernie's guests, which tells you how famous she is!</clue>
<clue>The Hampton family come from New Jersey, but were in Greece working for a major airline when their only child was born; he isn't the man who grew up to be a minor movie start playing minor roles in minor films.</clue>
<clue>Strangely enough, the country singer, who sings with a strong Tennessee accent, was born in Israel and raised in Alaska.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="First name">
<item>Bernie</item>
<item>Dudley</item>
<item>Glenda</item>
<item>Luke</item>
<item>Nancy</item>
</category>
<category name="Surname">
<item>Dayton</item>
<item>Fairbanks</item>
<item>Hampton</item>
<item>Portland</item>
<item>Troy</item>
</category>
<category name="Occupation">
<item>Country singer</item>
<item>Film actor</item>
<item>Golfer</item>
<item>Sprinter</item>
<item>Talk show host</item>
</category>
<category name="Land of birth">
<item>Australia</item>
<item>Greece</item>
<item>Israel</item>
<item>Spain</item>
<item>Thailand</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Bernie, Hampton, Talk show host, Greece},{Dudley, Dayton, Film actor, Australia},{Glenda, Troy, Golfer, Thailand},{Luke, Fairbanks, Sprinter, Spain},{Nancy, Portland, Country singer, Israel}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="43" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "gender">
<title>Dinah's Diner</title>
<text>
<preamble>A new eatery has opened in Stonekeigh, along the lines of a 1950s American diner. It's actually an old railway carriage with the wheels taken off and plonked in a car park just off the High Street, but it's a start. Its owner, Dinah Mow, has tried hard to keep the 50s Americana theme with posters, rock'n'roll msuic and waitresses, who are contractually obliged to chew gum, using diner slang. But not being fully aware of the lingo, they have made it up themselves. From the clues, can you name the waitress dealing with each customer, the diner slang she's used for the particular bread product ordered and the food to which she refers.</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>It wasn't Sonia Servitte, who was taking Chuck Chowdon's order, who called out '...on a slab' at the end of the order, which in Dinah's Diner's diner slang means 'on toast'.</clue>
<clue>Pauline Putterway's waitress nodded and chewed as Pauline made her order and finished her shouted order to the kitchen with '...crusty', by which she didn't mean on a French baguette.</clue>
<clue>Terry Tukkin ordered a bacon bap, but wasn't attended to by waitress Olivia O'Stesse whose customer didn't order the roll.</clue>
<clue>Grace Garsonne listened to her customer, called out the order and then, after a precisely timed pause, added '...kneaded!'</clue>
<clue>Waitress Penny Paige took the order for a sandwich from a male customer; Muriel Mayde served a lady.</clue>
<clue>It wasn't Wilf Wolfett's server who called out the order '...by the baker'.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="Customer">
<item>Chuck Chowdown</item>
<item>Natalie Nosh</item>
<item>Pauline Putterway</item>
<item>Terry Tukkin</item>
<item>Wilf Wolfett</item>
</category>
<category name="Waitress">
<item>Grace Garsonne</item>
<item>Muriel Mayde</item>
<item>Olivia O'Stesse</item>
<item>Penny Paige</item>
<item>Sonia Servitte</item>
</category>
<category name="Slang">
<item>By the baker</item>
<item>Crusty</item>
<item>In the dough</item>
<item>Kneaded</item>
<item>On a slab</item>
</category>
<category name="Order">
<item>Baguette</item>
<item>Bap</item>
<item>Roll</item>
<item>Sandwich</item>
<item>Toast</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Chuck Chowdown, Sonia Servitte, By the baker, Baguette},{Natalie Nosh, Olivia O'Stesse, On a slab, Toast},{Pauline Putterway, Muriel Mayde, Crusty, Roll},{Terry Tukking, Grace Garsonne, Kneaded, Bap},{Wilf Wolfett, Penny Paige, In the dough, Sandwich}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="44" size="4x5" ordering="alphabet" semantic = "sister's daughter">
<title>Sew What?</title>
<text>
<preamble>Five neighbours living in Eddsbury's Cotton Street, all keen seamstresses, have gathered in Jill Cheyne's home so that they can work on their latest projects while sharing gossip, a cup of tea and a slice of her famous Madeira cake. From the information here, can you work out each woman's full name, what she is making and who it is for?</preamble>
<hints>
<clue>Both Louise, who is making a garment she'll wear herself, and the woman making the red sports shirt have surnames beginning with a letter in the first half of the alphabet.</clue>
<clue>Mrs Glover is working on a pair of black trousers.</clue>
<clue>One of the women is making a tabard - white, with a coat of arms front and back - for her son Wayne to wear in a school pageant.</clue>
<clue>Mrs Tack's forename appears later in the alphabetical list than that of the woman who is working on something for her daughter.</clue>
<clue>Mrs Hemming is making something for her sister Mary's daughter to wear.</clue>
<clue>Angela is working on a blue and white Japanese-style Kimono (is there any other style?); Dora is not sewing up a garment for her sister - in fact, she's an only child.</clue>
<clue>Mrs Quilter isn't making a kimono or a cocktail dress.</clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="First name">
<item>Angela</item>
<item>Doris</item>
<item>Jill</item>
<item>Louise</item>
<item>Sonia</item>
</category>
<category name="Surname">
<item>Cheyne</item>
<item>Glover</item>
<item>Hemming</item>
<item>Quilter</item>
<item>Tack</item>
</category>
<category name="Garment">
<item>Cocktail dress</item>
<item>Kimono</item>
<item>Sports shirt</item>
<item>Tabard</item>
<item>Trousers</item>
</category>
<category name="For">
<item>Daughter</item>
<item>Herself</item>
<item>Niece</item>
<item>Sister</item>
<item>Son</item>
</category>
<solution>{{Angela, Hemming, Kimono, Niece},{Doris, Quilter, Tabard, Son},{Jill, Cheyne, Sports shirt, Daughter},{Louise, Glover, Trousers, Herself},{Sonia, Tack, Cocktail dress, Sister}}</solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="45" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "">
<title></title>
<text>
<preamble></preamble>
<hints>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<solution></solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="46" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "">
<title></title>
<text>
<preamble></preamble>
<hints>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<solution></solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="47" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "">
<title></title>
<text>
<preamble></preamble>
<hints>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<solution></solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="48" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "">
<title></title>
<text>
<preamble></preamble>
<hints>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<solution></solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="49" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "">
<title></title>
<text>
<preamble></preamble>
<hints>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<solution></solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
<puzzle id="50" size="4x5" ordering="" semantic = "">
<title></title>
<text>
<preamble></preamble>
<hints>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
<clue></clue>
</hints>
</text>
<box>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<category name="">
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
<item></item>
</category>
<solution></solution>
</box>
</puzzle>
</folio>